Two sisters divided for the love of a king.
The Other Boleyn Girl is a drama, romance, history
film directed by Justin Chadwick.
A sumptuous and sensual tale of intrigue, romance and betrayal set against the backdrop of a defining moment in European history: two beautiful
sisters, Anne and Mary Boleyn, driven by their family's blind ambition, compete for the love of the handsome and passionate King Henry VIII.
Anne Boleyn, played by Natalie Portman.
Mary Boleyn, played by Scarlett Johansson.
Henry Tudor, played by Eric Bana.
George Boleyn, played by Jim Sturgess.
Sir Thomas Boleyn, played by Mark Rylance.
Lady Elizabeth Boleyn, played by Kristin Scott Thomas.
The Other Boleyn Girl is a 2008 historical romantic
drama film directed by Justin Chadwick.
The screenplay by Peter Morgan was adapted from Philippa
Gregory’s 2001 novel of the same name.
It is a fictionalised account of the lives of 16th-century English aristocrats Mary Boleyn, mistress of
King Henry VIII, and her sister, Anne, who became the monarch's ill-fated second wife.
The film was released on February 29, 2008.
The film explores themes of sibling relationship, based on
novel or book, england, kingdom, politics.
The tone is emotional.